Simon Hudson

Front-End Developer

hellosimonhudson.com / linkedin.com/in/hellosimonhudson

I am an experienced Front-End Developer who uses HTML, CSS, JavaScript and TypeScript to create accessible and usable websites and applications. I am passionate about web accessibility and how to build for assistive technologies. I'm also a big fan of test-driven development, clean code, and striving for simple solutions to complex problems.

Core skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, React, Sass, Node.js, Next.js, Express, Styled Components, Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library, Mocha, Chai, Nightwatch, Cypress, Accessibility/WCAG Guidelines

Experience

Senior Software Engineer – Admiral Group (Nov 2023 – present)

 Working with a globally distributed team on Admiral's Pet Insurance product, using the <u>FintechOS platform</u> to configure and orchestrate all aspects of the proposition, including policies, back-office functions, and user journeys.

Product Developer – Experian (May 2014 – Nov 2023)

- Built and maintained Experian's <u>Marketplace web app</u>, primarily using Node, React and Styled Components.
- Wrote extensive unit tests to meet minimum threshold requirements, which also ensured the AWS-based CI/CD pipeline could run with confidence, allowing multiple releases per day.
- Championed accessibility standards across the entire team. Created suite of automation and unit tests to verify journeys against WCAG 2.1 AA standards. Acted as point-ofcontact for accessibility issues and helped train Developers/QA in common accessibility issues and how to test using assistive technologies.
- Acted as Security Champion for the team. Proactively reviewed scans from tooling such as Veracode and Aguasec. Liaised with Security Champions from other teams.
- As a long-standing member of the team, I acted as a mentor/buddy to new starters and graduates, giving support and feedback where required.

Senior Front-End Developer – 4energy (July 2013 – May 2014)

- Creating monitoring software for data centre cooling systems.
- Migrated existing PHP-based front-end over to use Kendo UI library and Apache Velocity templating language, as well as Sass for CSS.

Front-End Developer – NHS Choices (Capita) (May 2009 – Jan 2010 / Apr 2010 – Jul 2013)

- Worked on one of the largest websites in Europe (www.nhs.uk)
- Wrote front-end code to very high standard, and liaised with back-end developers to integrate it into the Sharepoint/.NET solution
- As a government website, it required strict attention to accessibility standards. Had regular audits from external parties such as <u>R.N.I.B</u> and <u>AbilityNet</u>, and would implement updates based on their recommendations.

Senior Web Designer – Manheim Europe (Oct 2006 – May 2009)

- Worked on a range of projects from small banner adverts and HTML e-mails, through to designing and implementing a group-wide intranet based on Drupal CMS.
- Solely responsible for designing and building websites for the company's operations in continental Europe.
- Assisted on digital and print projects for high-profile clients such as BMW, Toyota and Daimler Chrysler.
- Assisted the Design Manager in the running of the department and acted as the main point-of-contact in his absence.

Graphic Designer/Web Developer – University of Derby Students Union (Nov 2004 – Sep 2006)

- Working part-time during my studies, this role offered me the chance to gain real-world experience whilst studying.
- Assisted the lead designer in all aspects of Union marketing, from booklets and posters for events, through to maintenance of the Union website and contributing to the award-winning monthly student magazine.
- Given the responsibility of re-designing, building and launching the microsite for the Union's satellite campus in Buxton.

Education

University of Derby (2004 – 2006)

Foundation Degree in New Media Design & Production (Pass with Merit)

Derby College (1997 – 1999)

A Level English (Language & Literature), Psychology, Media Studies

Chellaston Secondary School, Derby (1992 – 1997)

9 G.C.S.E Higher Grade passes

References

Available on request